<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trevor&#39;s Data Science Portfolio on Trevor Seguin</title>
    <link>./</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trevor&#39;s Data Science Portfolio on Trevor Seguin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Product Recommender</title>
      <link>./post/project_1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/project_1.html</guid>
      <description>This project uses Amazon product review and meta data up to 2018 to create recommender systems: one approach was write a commandline program that would return personalized recommendations for a user profile, which involved thorough evaluation of models using both collaborative and content-based filtering methods. The github repo shows the model evaluation in detail. I went with the SVD algorithm (a collaborative filtering method) for the commandline approach, and then made a Flask web app with pre-computed sets of products which are similar to a specific product (content-based method).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>./contact.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./contact.html</guid>
      <description>         Email: tseguin715@gmail.com   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/trevor-seguin   Github: https://www.github.com/tseguin715    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors associated with online purchasing behavior</title>
      <link>./post/project_2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/project_2.html</guid>
      <description>This project models purchasing behavior of an e-commerce website in terms of analytics such as number of pages viewed, type of web page visited and duration (e.g. product related or administrative pages), and other features such as &amp;lsquo;bounce rates&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;exit rates&amp;rsquo;, etc. associated with a binary target variable (1 = purchase; 0 = no purchase). The overarching goal was to tune a model to the purchasing behavior and derive feature importance - i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The X-Files: Insights from data</title>
      <link>./post/project_3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./post/project_3.html</guid>
      <description>Here I scraped and cleaned data such as IMDB ratings, writer, director, number of viewers, episode transcripts, category (&amp;lsquo;Mythology&amp;rsquo; or not) for every episode of The X-Files, and did a deep dive to understand how these features correlate with episode rating. I used statistical testing methods such as Welch&amp;rsquo;s T-test and the Mann-Whitney U test to probe the influence of writers, directors and characters on episode rating, and modelled the ratings progression through the series with a number of methods to understand where the show peaks and which episodes are rated more highly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>